JONATHAN HOLLINGER

232 TAYLOR DR · LEXINGTON, KY 40511 · (859) 552-5292 · <u>JONATHANMHOLLINGER@GMAIL.COM</u> <u>https://jmhollinger.github.io/lclt/</u>

SUMMARY

Experienced public sector administrator, policy analyst, and technology solution architect with a focus on housing policy and community development. Significant accomplishments include management of the \$40 million Town Branch Commons project, the creation of the Lexington Affordable Housing Fund, management of the Lexington Vacant Property Review Commission, and the implementation of a property data analytics platform in more than 40 cities, land banks, and nonprofit organizations. Skills include:

Housing Policy

• Board Management

Residential Construction

Sales and Marketing

Statistical Modeling

Financial Management

Project Management

• Database Development

Data Analysis

Fundraising

Geospatial Analysis

Web Development

EXPERIENCE

LEAD SOLUTIONS MANAGER

TOLEMI

August 2017 – Present

- Managed over 40 new implementations of property analytics platform for cities, land banks, and redevelopment authorities.
- Connected disparate data sources from internal systems to produce analysis for land bank pricing, targeted acquisition programs, proactive code enforcement, and other policy initiatives.
- Gathered information from clients about their goals, policies and programs to build technology solutions to achieve their objectives.
- Built data models that scored parcels based on data-driven criteria; scores include fire risk, vacancy prediction, neighborhood health scoring, gentrification risk, and others.
- Helped clients identify geographic priority areas based on data.
- Developed scripts to extract data from difficult to integrate client data sources.
- Wrote data transformations in SQL and other languages to clean and standardize data for analysis.

DIRECTOR OF PROJECT MANAGEMENT

CITY OF LEXINGTON, MAYOR'S OFFICE

December 2016 - August 2017

- Secured \$14.1M federal <u>TIGER grant</u> for the project, the first ever for Lexington.
- Supported and advocated for the Town Branch Fund. Their efforts have raised over \$6M in private donations for the project.

- Secured <u>SCAPE Landscape Architecture</u> to complete their design vision for the project and managed the masterplan design process.
- Developed a custom project management dashboard to communicate project status to stakeholders.

SENIOR ADMINISTRATIVE OFFICER

CITY OF LEXINGTON, DEPARTMENT OF PLANNING, PRESERVATION, AND DEVELOPMENT

December 2013 - December 2016

- Managed Lexington's Vacant Property Review Commission.
- Assisted with the creation of Lexington's Affordable Housing Fund.
- Assisted with major technology implementations, including new systems for Permitting and Code Enforcement.
- Created new systems for tracking department information, including automated data extraction processes, and data processing tools.
- Deployed and managed over 50 mobile devices (Apple iPad, Apple iPhone) to collect data in the field and improve efficiency.
- Created public engagement tools to collect and use public input to design projects.
- Assisted with management of the department including more than 100 employees and a multi-milliondollar budget.

LEGISLATIVE AIDE

CITY OF LEXINGTON, COUNCIL OFFICE

June 2010 - December 2013

- Performed and presented extensive research on the Police and Fire Pension Fund, ultimately leading to landmark pension reform legislation in 2013.
- Served as the primary staff person for the Council budget review process in 2011, 2012, and 2013.
- Managed all constituent relations for the 10th District Council Office and presented information to the general public on LFUCG programs and projects.
- Created a custom database to track complaints, issues, and other contacts with the Council Office.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF KENTUCKY, MARTIN SCHOOL OF PUBLIC POLICY AND ADMINISTRATION

MASTER OF PUBLIC ADMINISTRATION August 2009 - May 2011

UNIVERSITY OF KENTUCKY, COLLEGE OF FINE ARTS

BACHELOR OF ARTS, ARTS ADMINISTRATION August 2005 - May 2009

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Microsoft Office Applications (Expert Level)
- Visual Basic for Applications
- Statistical Research Methods and Software (SPSS, R)
- Actuarial and Financial Analysis
- Database Management
- SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Python
- Geospatial Analysis (PostGIS, QGIS, ArcGIS)
- Cloud Services Configuration (AWS, Heroku)
- Google Analytics
- REST API Integrations

PUBLICATIONS

KENTUCKY PENSION REFORM UNDER SENATE BILL 2

KENTUCKY BENCH AND BAR, MARCH 2014
R. Douglas Martin, J.D. Chaney, Jonathan M. Hollinger

NEW ACCOUNTING STANDARDS FOR GOVERNMENT PENSIONS

KENTUCKY BENCH AND BAR, MARCH 2014
Lee Ann Watters, Jonathan M. Hollinger, and R. Douglas Martin

PUBLIC ART MASTER PLANNING FOR MUNICIPAL GOVERNMENTS: CORE COMPONENTS AND COMMON PRACTICES

UKNOWLEDGE - UNIVERSITY OF KENTUCKY, 2011 Jonathan M. Hollinger